<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtubekids.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<link rel="self" href="http://www.youtubekids.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLEeIyWKd-HQ4MMlJefvgkg0tdAN9Yl4Wc"/>
<id>yt:playlist:PLEeIyWKd-HQ4MMlJefvgkg0tdAN9Yl4Wc</id>
<yt:playlistId>PLEeIyWKd-HQ4MMlJefvgkg0tdAN9Yl4Wc</yt:playlistId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learn To Talk with Ms Rachel</title>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2022-12-11T21:34:58+00:00</published>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:yBj9Qlpwjcs</id>
<yt:videoId>yBj9Qlpwjcs</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learning with Ms Rachel | Learn Words and Colors for Toddlers | Educational Kids Videos | Animals</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=yBj9Qlpwjcs"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2022-09-13T13:00:10+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-22T20:49:18+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Learning with Ms Rachel | Learn Words and Colors for Toddlers | Educational Kids Videos | Animals</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/yBj9Qlpwjcs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/yBj9Qlpwjcs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Learn with a real teacher, Ms Rachel! You can trust Ms Rachel because her program is backed by research by and designed to encourage speech development, language development and help toddlers meet important learning standards! Her educational videos for toddlers are incredibly interactive. They are active screen time, not passive screen time. Watch how your toddler engages with her, fills in words, sings dances and plays! It's time to learn to talk and grow their brain with Ms Rachel! Ms Rachel absolutely loves kids and is so passionate about teaching and early childhood development! Your toddler will love learning new words and colors in this educational and fun Toddler Learning Video. Your toddler will also learn about animals and animal sounds. Ms Rachel also always incorporates fun learning songs and dancing! She uses things that motivate children to use their voices and show them the power of communication such as surprise eggs and surprise toys. She will get your chid up, moving and singing! Ms Rachel has the best videos for kids because she has the education and experience with children needed to engage and inspire them to learn!  If you think your child may have a speech delay, definitely consult your pediatrician. You can also get an evaluation from a speech therapist. You may be able to get free speech therapy through early intervention so google “early intervention” with the name of your state and call the number. As a parent, you can request an evaluation. Getting help when they are as young as possible is so important.  Visit our page for more exciting learning videos for kids with Ms Rachel! With Ms Rachel’s phenomenal videos, your child will learn colors, learn animals, counting, abcs, phonics, pretend play, vocabulary development, emotions, social emotional development and more!  Visit our page for more learning videos with Ms Rachel such as learn to talk videos, first words videos, baby sign videos, baby learning videos, colors and counting videos, learn colors videos, preschool learning videos, a playground learning video, songs for toddlers, videos for toddlers, vocabulary development videos, videos for kids, kids videos, music class videos and more!  #toddlerlearning #learning #educationalvideosforkids #toddler #animals #animalsounds #kidsvideos #videosfortoddlers #videosforkids #learntotalk</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="138298" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="64702197"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:dnHWQwh1Iso</id>
<yt:videoId>dnHWQwh1Iso</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Talking Time with Ms Rachel - Baby Videos for Babies and Toddlers - Speech Delay Learning Video</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=dnHWQwh1Iso"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2021-04-06T13:00:12+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-08T17:52:32+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Talking Time with Ms Rachel - Baby Videos for Babies and Toddlers - Speech Delay Learning Video</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/dnHWQwh1Iso?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/dnHWQwh1Iso/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>“Talking Time” baby videos aim to encourage speech and communication in babies and toddlers. Ms Rachel speaks very slowly and clearly to model language for little ones. She also encourages signs, gestures, and imitation, which are building blocks of speech. If you think your child has a speech delay, definitely talk to your pediatrician now. You may qualify for free speech therapy through your state's early intervention program. You can also get evaluated by a speech therapist and seek private speech therapy. The earlier you do this, the better! Rachel is not a speech therapist herself. She is a music teacher with a masters in music education. (We do have a speech therapist on our team.) A wonderful speech therapy practice we recommend is Chatterbox NYC, where Rachel learned many techniques and strategies! Rachel has also been a toddler teacher for children with special needs including speech delays, developmental delays, down syndrome, cerebral palsy, autism (ASD) and apraxia. She has also worked in homes to support families with children with special needs. She is very passionate about early childhood education and early intervention and believes all children are gifted, brilliant, precious and our teachers as well! We have many educational videos for babies, toddlers and preschoolers on our YouTube Page, so please check out more of our learning videos for toddlers! We’d love to have you as part of the Songs for Littles family! Check out our Talking Time, Learn To Talk, First Words, Talking Toddler, Baby Sign Language, Phonics, music classes and Preschool for Littles Videos! This video also includes a section of very slow speech practice at the very end which may be helpful for children with speech delays and childhood apraxia of speech. It also includes a section at the end of songs and nursery rhymes to go with the themes of the episode, which also help with speech and language development. It includes baby sign language throughout the video, which is shown to enhance speech development and show the power of communication. It will not impede speech development. We have many more baby videos for babies to watch, toddler learning videos and preschool learning videos on our YouTube page. We are incredibly passionate about early childhood education! We put a lot of time, care and research into each learning video for toddlers we create. Our videos are interactive screen time not not passive screen time because research shows that this is most beneficial. We also have full baby music classes, full toddler music classes and full preschool music classes. We use simple songs, music, basic sign language, and first words to build vocabulary. We have many videos with fun baby songs and toddler songs, and we also have videos that aim to help with speech development and first words. We also have preschool videos for preschoolers. These are great videos for teaching toddlers preschool readiness skills! They are full of preschool lessons that are great for 1 year olds, 2 year olds, 3 year olds, 4 year olds and even 5 year olds or older! We also have preschool music classes. Many people are involved in designing our videos. On our team we have: a speech-language pathologist, a reading specialist, a Broadway musician, an early childhood curriculum specialist, a child and family therapist, and award-winning songwriters! If you have a baby, 1 year old, 2 year old, 3 year old, 4 year old or 5 year old, our channel is perfect for you! These are some of the best educational videos for kids you will find. Our Learn To Talk for Toddlers videos show First Words and functional speech may be helpful to children with speech delays or speech disorders. These are very interactive baby videos for babies to watch. We put your baby first and not entertainment value. Even parents enjoy the educational videos we create. Our videos are wonderful for preschoolers, kindergarteners and even elementary students. Our videos are in English and we purposefully speak slowly and clearly for optimal learning. We hope you enjoy our English learning videos for toddlers. #babyvideos #speechdelay #speech #babysignlanguage #toddlerlearningvideo #learntotalk #educationalvideosfortoddlers #babies #videosforbabies #toddlervideos #talkingtoddler #talkingtime Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher and has a sweet 2-year-old boy who inspired her online baby music classes and learning videos! ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website www.songsforlittles.com ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/ #SongsForLittles</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="165420" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="92125156"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:6nRAv1_UFJs</id>
<yt:videoId>6nRAv1_UFJs</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learn To Talk for Toddlers - First Words - Speech For 2 Year Old - Speech Delay Learning - Apraxia</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=6nRAv1_UFJs"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2020-12-29T14:00:21+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-14T15:02:40+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Learn To Talk for Toddlers - First Words - Speech For 2 Year Old - Speech Delay Learning - Apraxia</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/6nRAv1_UFJs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/6nRAv1_UFJs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Does your toddler have a speech delay? Talk to your pediatrician and also call early intervention! The sooner you get help, the better. Definitely try to get speech therapy for your child. We hope our videos are also helpful for your little one! Ms Rachel's son had a speech delay, and she became very passionate about trying to help toddlers with their language development. Learn To Talk for Toddlers videos show First Words and functional speech for babies, toddlers, 1 year olds, 2 year olds, 3 year olds and older! We show a mouth close-up, which may be helpful to children with speech delays and apraxia. This video focuses on over 25 first words! Ms Rachel is a master at encouraging speech In this toddler learning video we show many common first words and functional words that can help toddlers communicate what they need and want. Words focused on include: Mama, Dada, Hi, Me, More, Go, Help, Eat, Open, I, Want, No, Ya, Mama, Dada, Ball, On, One, Two, Three, Done, Banana, Teddy Bear, Baby, Bubble, Down, Tummy, Peek-A-Boo, Bye. As well as speech practice sessions, we introduce simple songs that help children with gestures and language. Gestures and imitation are important skills for toddlers! We also demonstrate another important skill for toddlers, pretend and imaginative play. Our videos have also been helpful for children with autism. If you think your child has a speech delay, definitely talk to your pediatrician. You may qualify for free speech therapy through your state's early intervention program. You can also get evaluated by a speech therapist. Rachel is not a speech therapist, but on several videos she has worked with speech therapists to share helpful techniques for speech practice. "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission. On our YouTube page we also have more baby learning videos, toddler learning videos and preschool learning videos. In our educational videos for babies, toddlers and preschoolers, we work on speech and language, milestones, gestures, baby sign language, pretend play, flash cards, social emotional learning, dramatic play, art, music, math, science, circle time, finger plays, singing, dancing, exercises, sensory play and more! Rachel has worked with children with special needs including autism, down syndrome, speech delays, apraxia, cerebral palsy and global developmental delays. She believes all children are smart, important, gifted, valuable and our teachers. We put your baby first and not entertainment value. That is why there is no loud music during the presentation of words. #learntotalk #learntotalkfortoddlers #firstwords #apraxia #speechdelay #firstwordsforbabies #firstwordsfortoddlers #educationalvideos #flashcards #babies #toddlers #1yearold #2yearold #3yearold #milestones #babiesfirstwords Rachel has taught preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher and has a sweet 2-year-old boy who inspired her online baby music classes and learning videos! ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website www.songsforlittles.com ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/ Our video are great for your 1 year old, 2 year old, 3 year old, 4 year old and 5 year old! Even parents enjoy the educational videos we create. Our videos are wonderful for preschoolers, kindergarteners and even elementary students. Our videos are in English and we purposefully speak slowly and clearly for optimal learning. We hope you enjoy our English learning videos for toddlers.</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="62878" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="39536552"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:1IEGrjMC88M</id>
<yt:videoId>1IEGrjMC88M</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learn To Talk with Ms Rachel - Learning at an Outdoor Playground - Toddler Videos - Toddler Shows</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=1IEGrjMC88M"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2020-09-18T14:00:13+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-07T13:54:27+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Learn To Talk with Ms Rachel - Learning at an Outdoor Playground - Toddler Videos - Toddler Shows</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/1IEGrjMC88M?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/1IEGrjMC88M/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Our Learn To Talk videos for toddlers aim to help children practice first words, speech, songs and signs! This toddler learning video takes place at an outdoor playground to motivate children to use language and to model social emotional skills such as asking a friend to play and taking turns. These are two very important preschool skills that help children succeed! Ms Rachel is not a speech therapist, but she collaborates with speech therapists and works to make videos that encourage practice of speech and language. She also emphasizes signs, gestures, and imitation, which are three building blocks of language development. As a music educator with a masters in music education, she often uses songs to practice these skills. Rachel also works hard to make her videos very interactive, because interactive screen time is shown to have a much greater benefit than passive screen time. If you suspect your child has a speech delay, definitely talk to your pediatrician. You may be eligible for free speech therapy through your state’s early intervention program! "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino  The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission. On our YouTube page we have many speech practice videos, full music classes and full preschool classes! We have classes for babies, toddlers, young children and kindergarten through second grade. We have videos for babies, 1 year olds, 2 year olds, 3 year olds, 4 year olds and 5 year olds! I hope you enjoy our toddler shows that are very educational videos! We also have baby sign language videos! We hope our videos help children learn to talk, bring them joy and create bonding experiences! Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher at preschools, daycares and at a school for children with special needs and has worked with children with autism, speech delays, cerebral palsy, down syndrome and developmental delays. She believes every child is gifted in their own way and is also a teacher to her. ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website www.songsforlittles.com ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/ #learntotalk #speechdelaytoddler #toddlerspeechdelay #toddlerlearningvideos #toddlerlearningvideo #learningvideosfortoddlers #toddlersongs #educationalvideosfortoddlers #toddlervideos #toddler #toddlerlearning #speech #education #kidssongs #msrachel #songsforlittles #toddlers #educational #learnenglish #playground #teacher</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="76238" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="57789102"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:XtHZ_8ILGgY</id>
<yt:videoId>XtHZ_8ILGgY</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learn To Talk - Toddler Learning Video - Learn Colors with Crayon Surprises - Speech Delay - Baby</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=XtHZ_8ILGgY"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2021-02-22T13:00:12+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-17T15:52:10+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Learn To Talk - Toddler Learning Video - Learn Colors with Crayon Surprises - Speech Delay - Baby</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/XtHZ_8ILGgY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/XtHZ_8ILGgY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Learn to Talk with Ms Rachel with this Toddler Learning Video! The toy used in this video has small parts and is not for children under 3 years old. This educational video for toddlers includes speech practice, learning colors, phonics, pretend play skills, simple songs, animals, first words, first sentences, letters and sign language! We will also learn colors with giant crayon surprises! We will open each color giant crayon and find fun giant crayon surprises that inspire us to sing simple songs that help with speech and language development, gestures, imitation and are so much fun! We’ll learn each color of the rainbow with these fun, engaging surprises! Our songs for toddlers will also encourage kids to get up and move and exercise! Something unique about our learning videos is a teacher, Ms Rachel, is on screen modeling language, gestures, pretend play and being incredibly interactive with viewers. We also show her mouth close up so children can focus on how sounds and words are formed. This may help children with speech development. If you think your child has a speech delay, definitely talk to your pediatrician. You may qualify for free speech therapy through your state's early intervention program. You can also get evaluated by a speech therapist. For some of our videos, I worked with the brilliant speech language pathologists (speech therapists) at Chatterbox NYC. You can find them at www.chatterboxnyc.com I am not a speech therapist myself. I am a music teacher with a masters in music education. We have many more baby learning videos, toddler learning videos and preschool learning videos. We are incredibly passionate about early childhood education! If you are looking for the best learning videos, you will see how much time, care and research we put into each toddler video we create. Rachel uses single words, simple sentences and speaks slowly so children can really hear the language. This video also includes a section of very slow speech practice which may be helpful for children with speech delays and apraxia. We aim for our videos to be incredibly interactive and engaging, not passive watching because research shows that this is most beneficial. We use simple songs, fun sounds, music, basic sign language, and first words to build vocabulary. I show gestures and signs because are they are incredibly important building blocks for language development. We have many different kids of videos for babies and toddlers on our channel. We have full baby music classes and full toddler music classes. We have many videos with fun baby songs and toddler songs, and we also have videos that aim to help with speech development and first words. We also have preschool videos for preschoolers. These are great videos for teaching toddlers preschool readiness skills! They are full of preschool lessons that are great for 1 year olds, 2 year olds, 3 year olds, 4 year olds and even 5 year olds or older! We also have preschool music classes. Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a masters degree in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher at a school for children with special needs including autism, apraxia, speech delays, developmental delays, down syndrome and cerebral palsy. Many people are involved in designing our videos. On our team we have: speech-language pathologists, a reading specialist, a Broadway musician, an early childhood curriculum specialist, a child and family therapist, and award-winning songwriters! This video is edited by Aron Accurso of Songs for Littles and Simone Kiseiel, the founder of Magic Dog Productions. These are some of the best educational videos for kids you will find. Our Learn To Talk for Toddlers videos show First Words and functional speech for babies, toddlers, 1 year olds, 2 year olds, 3 year olds and older! We put your baby first and not entertainment value. That is why there is no loud music during the presentation of words. #learntotalk #learncolors #toddlerlearningvideo #bestlearningvideofortoddlers #learningvideofortoddlers #crayonsurprises #giantcrayons #speechfortoddlers #learntotalkfortoddlers #firstwords #apraxia #speechdelay #firstwordsforbabies #firstwordsfortoddlers #educationalvideos #flashcards #babies #toddlers #babiesfirstwords #phonics #earlyintervention Even parents enjoy the educational videos we create. Our videos are wonderful for preschoolers and kindergarteners. Our videos are in English and we purposefully speak slowly and clearly for optimal learning. We hope you enjoy our English learning videos for toddlers. #SongsForLittles #speechdelay #learning #learn #learncolors #msrachel #toddlerlearningvideos #toddlers #speech #toddlerlearningvideos #kidssongs #songsforlittles #education #educational #learnenglish #toddler #toddlersongs #crayons #toys #toy #learntotalk</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="85000" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="79500583"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:05Vj6rGCauQ</id>
<yt:videoId>05Vj6rGCauQ</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Videos for Babies and Toddlers - Animal Sounds, First Words, Toddler Speech Learning Exercises</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=05Vj6rGCauQ"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2020-12-10T16:00:11+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-21T23:02:32+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Videos for Babies and Toddlers - Animal Sounds, First Words, Toddler Speech Learning Exercises</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/05Vj6rGCauQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/05Vj6rGCauQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Our videos for babies and toddlers teach animal sounds, first words and encourage baby and toddler speech and language development learning. We use techniques recommended by speech therapists. Join us as we learn about pets and animal sounds in this fun “Talking Time” video! After pets, you will see some of our farm animal video and then some slow speech exercises. We hope you find the toddler speech learning exercises, activities and techniques helpful. If you think your child may have a speech delay, talk to your pediatrician. You may qualify for free speech therapy through early intervention. You can also get an assessment from a speech therapist. The sooner you get help, the better! Just to be clear, we ourselves are not speech therapists. Rachel has a masters in music education and teaches preschool music. She has also taught many toddler classes. If you are in New York City and are seeking a speech therapist, check out www.chatterboxnyc.com The brilliant speech therapists at Chatterbox are highly recommended and helped with our “Speech Techniques for Toddlers” video. We also include toddler songs and baby songs in our toddler speech learning videos. Simple songs can help the development of language and gestures! Gestures and imitation are building blocks that help with language development. We also include some sign language and pretend play. Baby sign language can help with the development of language and will not impede the development of language and speech. We also model pretend play. Pretend play is an important toddler skill. In this video we will go over the following animal sounds: Dog, cat, bunny rabbit and farm animals, cow, duck, pig, sheep and horse. Animal sounds are a great way to encourage your child to make sounds and experiment with their voice. A fun toy that may encourage language is a toy barn with toy farm animals. You can get right down on the floor at your child’s level and make the animal sounds. It may help to hold a toy by your mouth so they look at the way your mouth produces the sounds. This video may also be helpful to children with apraxia, autism, down syndrome and other developmental delays and special needs. We hope the speech activities, exercises, lessons and training are helpful! This video is great for a baby, 1 year old, 2 year old, 3 year old, 4 year old and even older! On our channel, we have many more speech practice videos (see our speech playlist) and we also have free preschool class videos (see our preschool class playlist) and full music classes! We have videos for babies, videos for toddlers and videos for kids. Our videos for toddlers are in English. In our videos we work on speech and language, milestones, gestures, pretend play, social emotional learning, dramatic play, art, music, math, science, circle time, finger plays, sensory play and many more activities! We’d love for you to become part of our Songs for Littles family! If you are looking for videos for babies, 1 year olds, 2 year olds, 3 year olds, 4 year olds or even 5 year olds, our videos will be excellent choices. #videosforbabies #videosfortoddlers #firstwords #animalsounds #toddlerspeech #animalsoundsfortoddlers #petsounds #farmanimalsounds #animalsoundsforbabies #speechdelay #speechfortoddlers #speechdevelopment #firstwords #farmanimals #babysignlanguage #animalsoundssong #apraxia #learningvideos Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher and has a sweet 2-year-old boy who inspired her online baby music classes and learning videos! ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website www.songsforlittles.com ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/ #SongsForLittles</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="70458" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="43040790"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:41vocyDRhLs</id>
<yt:videoId>41vocyDRhLs</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Speech Practice Video for Toddlers and Babies - Speech Delay Toddler - Learn To Talk Videos</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=41vocyDRhLs"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2020-07-09T18:00:53+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-12T01:08:51+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Speech Practice Video for Toddlers and Babies - Speech Delay Toddler - Learn To Talk Videos</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/41vocyDRhLs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/41vocyDRhLs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>This speech practice video for toddlers and babies encourages children to learn to talk. If your child has a speech delay, consult your pediatrician and a speech therapist. This video includes tips from Chatterbox NYC speech therapists. Ms Rachel, who is in the video, is not a speech therapist. This video is for toddlers, babies and has information for parents and caregivers. It focuses on speech and language development. Gestures and imitation are important in the development of speech and language. Pretend play and taking turns are also important. This speech video also uses simple songs to help practice gestures and imitation. In our educational videos for toddlers, gestures, speech, and creative play are practiced. You can find Chatterbox at chatterboxnyc.com They are brilliant speech language pathologists (SLPS) that offer virtual sessions. Other tips you may find helpful: Hold a toy that turns on, pops up, lights up etc away from the child. Say, “Ready, set…” and then if they make any sound, make the toy work. Then say, “YAY! You said “GO” If they cannot make any sounds, make the toy work when they look at you. This teaches them the power of their voice and communication. Don’t say, “No, say, Go” if they say “eh” or “ah” You want them to know that using their voice helps them get things! Any sound is celebrated! If your child is late on the milestone of pointing, you can help shape their hand into a point and have them point at something they want. Then give them the item the want. To teach the sign for more, you can give the child a little of their favorite food. Then say, “Do you want MORE?” and do the sign for more. Help them (hand over hand) do the sign for more. Then give them a little more of the food. Repeat many times. You can put a toy in a clear container with a cover so they have to ask for help getting it. You can put toys on tall shelves so they need to point and ask for the toy. You can sing songs with gestures and dance moves and encourage them to imitate. You can practice taking turns by doing things like stacking blocks and saying “YOUR TURN” then saying “MY TURN” and putting on a block You can slow down and simplify your words. Talk louder. You can also practice hand over hand with the gestures like doing the gestures of the wheels on the bus. #speechpracticevideo #speechvideosfortoddlers #speechvideoforbabies #learntotalk #talking time "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino  The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission. Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher and has a sweet 2-year-old boy who inspired her online baby music classes and learning videos! ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website https://www.songsforlittles.com/ ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/ #SongsForLittles</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="87087" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="39973622"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:78Mt3XlWHsI</id>
<yt:videoId>78Mt3XlWHsI</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learning Videos for Toddlers - Speech and Songs - Learn To Talk and Meet Milestones</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=78Mt3XlWHsI"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2020-08-13T12:00:24+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-23T23:28:30+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Learning Videos for Toddlers - Speech and Songs - Learn To Talk and Meet Milestones</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/78Mt3XlWHsI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/78Mt3XlWHsI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Our learning videos for toddlers help toddlers with speech, songs and meeting milestones. Songs are great for helping babies learn to talk. This is a mix of speech practice and kids songs for kids to enjoy and learn gestures, language and imitation. If your child has a speech delay, consult your pediatrician and a speech therapist. This video includes tips from Chatterbox NYC speech therapists. Rachel, who is in the video, is not a speech therapist. Our toddler learning videos are for toddlers and babies and have information about how to encourage language for parents and caregivers. They focus on speech, language development and some of the building blocks of communication like gestures, imitation, pretend play and turn taking. This speech video for toddlers also uses simple songs to help children learn and have fun! You can find Chatterbox at chatterboxnyc.com They are wonderful speech therapists that offer virtual sessions. Other tips you may find helpful: Talk slower, simplify language Narrate what you do all day and what your child does like a newscaster If your child is late on the milestone of pointing, you can help shape their hand into a point and have them point at something they want. Then give them the item the want. To teach the sign for more, you can give the child a little of their favorite food. Then say, “Do you want MORE?” and do the sign for more. Help them (hand over hand) do the sign for more. Then give them a little more of the food. Repeat many times. You can put a toy in a clear container with a cover so they have to ask for help getting it. You can put toys on tall shelves so they need to point and ask for the toy. You can sing songs with gestures and dance moves and encourage them to imitate. You can practice taking turns by doing things like stacking blocks and saying “YOUR TURN” then saying “MY TURN” and putting on a block You can also practice hand over hand with the gestures like doing the gestures of the wheels on the bus. #toddlervideos #learningsongs #songsforkids #kidssongs #speechdelay #speechpracticevideo #speechvideosfortoddlers #speechvideoforbabies #learntotalk #talkingtime "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino  The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission. Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher at a school for children with special needs including autism, speech delays, developmental delays, Down syndrome and cerebral palsy. ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website https://www.songsforlittles.com/ ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/maili... ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlit... #SongsForLittles</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="14235" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="9753826"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:nXzvYnkXQNI</id>
<yt:videoId>nXzvYnkXQNI</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Videos for Toddlers - Songs, Speech and Learning - Baby or Toddler Speech Delay - First Words</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=nXzvYnkXQNI"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2020-08-06T13:00:12+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-08T03:36:08+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Videos for Toddlers - Songs, Speech and Learning - Baby or Toddler Speech Delay - First Words</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/nXzvYnkXQNI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/nXzvYnkXQNI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Our videos for toddlers with songs, speech, and learning encourage first words. If your child has a speech delay, consult your pediatrician and a speech therapist. This video includes tips from Chatterbox NYC speech therapists. Rachel is not a speech therapist. This video is for toddlers, babies and has information for parents, grandparents, caregivers, and special grow-ups in children's lives. It focuses on speech and language development and practice. Gestures and imitation are very important in the development of speech and language. This toddler speech video also uses simple songs to help practice gestures and imitation. In our educational videos for toddlers and babies, gestures, speech, and creative play are practiced. We hope your toddler or baby enjoys this video. You can find Chatterbox at chatterboxnyc.com They are brilliant speech language pathologists (SLPS) that offer virtual sessions. We do not use much background music or animation because we want to keep the language very clear and the program simple. We try to make our show similar to a Zoom meeting with a teacher where you can learn at home. We make is slow paced on purpose. Other things you may find helpful: Speak and sing slowly to your child. Talk louder. Get down on the floor with them on their level so they can see your face well. Hold a toy that turns on, pops up, lights up etc away from the child. Say, “Ready, set…” and then if they make any sound, make the toy work. Then say, “YAY! You said “GO” If they cannot make any sounds, make the toy work when they look at you. This teaches them the power of their voice and communication. Don’t say, “No, say, Go” if they say “eh” or “ah” You want them to know that using their voice helps them get things! If your child is late on the milestone of pointing, you can help shape their hand into a point and have them point at something they want. Then give them the item the want. To teach the sign for more, you can give the child a little of their favorite food. Then say, “Do you want MORE” and do the sign for more. Help them (hand over hand) do the sign for more. Then give them a little more of the food. Repeat many times. You can put a toy in a clear container with a cover so they have to ask for help getting it. You can put toys on tall shelves so they need to point and ask for the toy. You can sing songs with gestures and dance moves and encourage them to imitate. You can practice taking turns by doing things like stacking blocks and saying “YOUR TURN” then saying “MY TURN” and putting on a block You can slow down and simplify your words. Talk louder. You can also practice hand over hand with the gestures like doing the gestures of the wheels on the bus. #videosfortoddlers #videosfortoddlerssongs #speechdelay #toddlerspeech #toddlerlearning #firstwords #toddlerspeechdelay #speechtherapy Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher and has a sweet 2-year-old boy who inspired her online baby music classes and learning videos! ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website https://www.songsforlittles.com/ ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/ #SongsForLittles</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="12909" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="7923553"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:Zuwuo5u0wYs</id>
<yt:videoId>Zuwuo5u0wYs</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Speech Videos for Toddlers and Babies - Early Intervention Activities and Baby Milestones Video</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=Zuwuo5u0wYs"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2020-07-30T17:04:35+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-10T13:56:38+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Speech Videos for Toddlers and Babies - Early Intervention Activities and Baby Milestones Video</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/Zuwuo5u0wYs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/Zuwuo5u0wYs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Our Speech Videos for Toddlers and Babies, "Talking Time" encourage speech and show early intervention activities. All babies and toddlers benefit from singing songs and nursery rhymes, rich pretend play, modeling language and interactions and floor time. It also lists some baby and toddler milestones to look for, such as gestures like point and waving, labeling and pointing to parts of body, imitating adults and pretend play. It's helpful to get down on the floor with your child at their level. If you have a very young baby, they can lay on their back and you can do the songs for them above them (don't forget daily "tummy time" which is very important!) If your child has a speech delay, consult your pediatrician and a speech therapist. This video includes tips from Chatterbox NYC speech therapists. Rachel, who is in the video, is not a speech therapist. She is a teacher. This video is for toddlers, babies and has information for parents and caregivers. It focuses on speech and language development. Gestures and imitation are important in the development of speech and language. Pretend play and taking turns are also important. This speech video also uses simple songs to help practice gestures and imitation. We also put kids songs in to give children a break and some fun time and movement so that they enjoy the videos. (Songs are also wonderful to practice language, imitation and gestures!) In our educational videos for toddlers, gestures, speech, and creative play are practiced. You can find Chatterbox at chatterboxnyc.com They are brilliant speech language pathologists (SLPS) that offer virtual sessions. Other tips you may find helpful: Hold a toy that turns on, pops up, lights up etc away from the child. Say, “Ready, set…” and then if they make any sound, make the toy work. Then say, “YAY! You said “GO” If they cannot make any sounds, make the toy work when they look at you. This teaches them the power of their voice and communication. Don’t say, “No, say, Go” if they say “eh” or “ah” You want them to know that using their voice helps them get things! Any sound is celebrated! If your child is late on the milestone of pointing, you can help shape their hand into a point and have them point at something they want. Then give them the item the want. To teach the sign for more, you can give the child a little of their favorite food. Then say, “Do you want MORE?” and do the sign for more. Help them (hand over hand) do the sign for more. Then give them a little more of the food. Repeat many times. You can put a toy in a clear container with a cover so they have to ask for help getting it. You can put toys on tall shelves so they need to point and ask for the toy. You can sing songs with gestures and dance moves and encourage them to imitate. You can practice taking turns by doing things like stacking blocks and saying “YOUR TURN” then saying “MY TURN” and putting on a block You can slow down and simplify your words. Talk louder. You can also practice hand over hand with the gestures like doing the gestures of the wheels on the bus. If they say "BALL" you can add on and say "BLUE BALL!" Narrate things you do and what they are doing during the day like a newscaster "Putting in! Putting toys in bucket. Put in. Put in." If they won't watch the video, you can try putting it on when they are eating and they are in a high chair (only if they are happy doing that) #speechvideosfortoddlers #speechvideos #earlyintervention #babymilestones #toddlermilestones #speechdelay #speechdelaytoddler "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino  The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission. Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher and has a sweet 2-year-old boy who inspired her online baby music classes and learning videos! ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website https://www.songsforlittles.com/ ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/ #SongsForLittles</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="33849" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="16756771"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:47MNn4bsmSw</id>
<yt:videoId>47MNn4bsmSw</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learn Animals with Ms Rachel for Toddlers - Animal Sounds, Farm Animals, Nursery Rhymes   Kids Songs</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=47MNn4bsmSw"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2022-04-26T14:00:11+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-11T13:46:31+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Learn Animals with Ms Rachel for Toddlers - Animal Sounds, Farm Animals, Nursery Rhymes   Kids Songs</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/47MNn4bsmSw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/47MNn4bsmSw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Have your toddler learn with a real teacher, Ms Rachel! Ms Rachel has packed so much important learning into this “Learn Animals with Ms Rachel” special! Not only does she teach farm animals, animal sounds, zoo animals, and baby animal names, she sneaks in learning concepts to prepare children for preschool, such as modeling “what questions,” gestures, first words, first sentences, 5 W Questions (Who, What, When, Where, Why) pretend play skills, counting, colors, shapes, numbers, letters and letter sounds! She includes fun nursery rhymes   kids songs that encourage movement and language development. She also teaches prepositions such as under, next to, on, behind, in and out! As always, you can count on Ms Rachel to encourage language, movement and engagement. She is a master at encouraging speech and making screen time active, not passive. This kind of screen time is more beneficial. Ms Rachel uses fun learning toys to engage and excite toddlers about learning and encourage speech. The learning standards and milestones she encourages range from 9 month old milestones like clapping to 5 year old milestones such as using the words and phrases “behind” and “next to” correctly and asking and answering “why questions.” Young children will be challenged to learn more and older siblings can watch and learn together with little ones. “Songs for Littles” is better screen time for bright toddlers! Buzz Feed called it “The best educational YouTube channel!”  If your child is not meeting milestones, let your pediatrician know and call Early Intervention for your state. Your child may qualify for free or very low cost therapies such as speech therapy, occupational therapy and physical therapy. You can also contact a private speech therapist (speech language pathologist) for an evaluation. It’s best to act early and get your child help as soon as possible.  Songs in this video include:  Old Macdonald Had A Farm Five Little Ducks  Mary Had A Little Lamb  Walkin’ At The Zoo  If You Should Meet An Elephant  Hop Little Bunnies  Tick Tock Cuckoo Clock  5 Little Monkeys Bananas Unite  Do You Know What Shape This Is?  Row, Row, Row Your Boat Bingo  Little Bo Peep  1-20 Song Itsy Bitsy Spider  Ants Go Marching ABCs Plus more!  Ms Rachel also teaches about taking care of our pets and being gentle with our pets! She teaches children about veterinarians. She also shows real pets and animals throughout the episode. The Old Macdonald Had A Farm with real animals will delight children and the Old MacDonald Baby Animals. Learn, grow and play along with Ms Rachel! Ms Rachel also learns about jungle animals and forest animals.  Visit our “Songs for Littles” YouTube Channel for many more baby learning videos, toddler learning videos, preschool learning videos, educational videos for toddlers, baby sign videos, learning videos for toddlers, videos for kids, baby learning videos for babies to watch, Learn To Talk videos, Talking Time, Baby Sensory Video, Talking Toddler, videos for 1 year olds, 2 year olds, 3 year olds, 4 year olds and 5 year olds! We have the best educational videos for toddlers and learning videos for kids. We know you’ll love this Old Macdonald Baby Animals video with kids songs and nursery rhymes! Your child will love Old Macdonald Nursery Rhymes and Kids Songs. Teacher Rachel loves you and is so proud of you!  #msrachel #songsforlittles #animalsounds #farmanimals #zooanimals #toddlerlearningvideos #babyanimals #oldmacdonald #kidssongs "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino  The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission.</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="204363" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="148956657"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:omcNGrnt7Sg</id>
<yt:videoId>omcNGrnt7Sg</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learn to Talk with Ms Rachel | Baby Learning Videos | Toddler Speech | Christmas | First Words</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=omcNGrnt7Sg"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2021-12-21T15:00:09+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-17T11:08:45+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Learn to Talk with Ms Rachel | Baby Learning Videos | Toddler Speech | Christmas | First Words</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/omcNGrnt7Sg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/omcNGrnt7Sg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Have your little one learn to talk with Ms Rachel, a real teacher! This learning video encourages language development, interaction and milestones.! We use a fun Christmas theme to get babies and toddlers talking, singing, dancing and celebrating! In this baby learning video, little ones will be encouraged to say first words such as up, down, hat, duck, ball, car, go, star and bye! Practice speech with us in this fun educational video for toddlers. Make sure your child is meeting their milestones! If you think your child may have a speech delay, definitely consult your pediatrician. You can also get an evaluation from a speech therapist. (Speech language pathologist) You may be able to get free speech therapy through early intervention so google “early intervention” with the name of your state and call the number now! As a parent, you can request an evaluation. Getting help when they are as young as possible is so important. "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino  The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission. If you are looking for more toddler learning videos, speech practice videos, early intervention skills videos, preschool class videos, educational videos for toddlers, learn to talk videos, or music class videos, videos for 2 year olds, videos for 3 year olds, 4 years olds or 5 year olds, our channel has them all! We have the best educational videos for kids! We also have baby learning videos for babies. Rachel has a master's in music education from NYU. She has had training in early childhood development from Harvard and Bank Street College. She is also working on a second masters in Early Childhood Development. She has been a toddler teacher at a preschool for children with special needs including autism, down syndrome, cerebral palsy, speech delays and other developmental delays. She believes all children are brilliant, magical and are our teachers as well. #learntotalk #babylearningvideos #babylearning #toddlerspeech #msrachel #missrachel #toddlerlearningvideo #babytalk #babyfirstwords #talkingtime #talkingtoddler ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="63186" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="41746746"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:8WLKPoOaNiM</id>
<yt:videoId>8WLKPoOaNiM</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Learn To Talk with Ms Rachel - Help Take Care of Dolls - Speech, Baby Sign - Doll turn into baby</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=8WLKPoOaNiM"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2021-03-16T13:00:12+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-08T18:37:45+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Learn To Talk with Ms Rachel - Help Take Care of Dolls - Speech, Baby Sign - Doll turn into baby</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/8WLKPoOaNiM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/8WLKPoOaNiM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>Help Ms Rachel care for baby dolls while learning how to talk, baby sign and pretend play (an important skill for toddlers!) This Toddler Learning Video aims to encourage babies and toddlers to learn to talk and practice speech, baby sign language and songs that help children learn gestures, imitation and language. It also includes pretend play skills with baby dolls playing and stuffed animals. Pretend play is important in development. We have many educational videos for babies, toddlers and preschoolers on our YouTube so please check out more of our learning videos for toddlers! We’d love to have you as part of the Songs for Littles family. Check out our Talking Time, Learn To Talk, First Words, Baby Sign Language, Phonics, music classes and Preschool for Littles Videos! If you think your child has a speech delay, definitely talk to your pediatrician now. You may qualify for free speech therapy through your state's early intervention program. You can also get evaluated by a speech therapist. The earlier you do this, the better! I am not a speech therapist myself. I am a music teacher with a masters in music education. We do have a speech therapist on our team. This video also includes a section of very slow speech practice at the end which may be helpful for children with speech delays and apraxia. It includes baby sign language throughout the video, which is shown to enhance speech development and show the power of communication. It will not impede speech development. I also model baby babbling because babble is important in the development of speech. "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino  The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission. Ms. Rachel has a masters degree in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher at a school for children with special needs including autism, apraxia, speech delays, developmental delays, down syndrome and cerebral palsy. She has worked in homes to support families with children with special needs. She believes all children are gifted, precious and our teachers as well! Have fun with Ms Rachel pretending the doll turn into baby and we have to be the babysitter! Help take care of babies We have many more baby learning videos, toddler learning videos and preschool learning videos on our YouTube page. We are incredibly passionate about early childhood education! We put a lot of time, care and research into each learning video for toddlers we create. Our videos are interactive screen time not not passive screen time because research shows that this is most beneficial. We also have full baby music classes and full toddler music classes. We use simple songs, music, basic sign language, and first words to build vocabulary. We also include social emotional learning. I show gestures and signs because are they are incredibly important building blocks for language development. We have many videos with fun baby songs and toddler songs, and we also have videos that aim to help with speech development and first words. We also have preschool videos for preschoolers. These are great videos for teaching toddlers preschool readiness skills! They are full of preschool lessons that are great for 1 year olds, 2 year olds, 3 year olds, 4 year olds and even 5 year olds or older! We also have preschool music classes. Many people are involved in designing our videos. On our team we have: a speech-language pathologist, a reading specialist, a Broadway musician, an early childhood curriculum specialist, a child and family therapist, and award-winning songwriters! If you have a baby, 1 year old, 2-year-old, 3-year-old, 4-year-old or 5-year-old, our channel is perfect for you! These are some of the best educational videos for kids you will find. Our Learn To Talk for Toddlers videos show First Words and functional speech may be helpful to children with speech delays or speech disorders. These are very interactive baby videos for babies to watch. We put your baby first and not entertainment value. That is why there is no loud music during the presentation of words. Even parents enjoy the educational videos we create. Our videos are wonderful for preschoolers, kindergarteners and even elementary students. Our videos are in English and we purposefully speak slowly and clearly for optimal learning. We hope you enjoy our English learning videos for toddlers. #toddlerlearningvideo #learntotalk #speech #speechdelay #babysignlanguage #educationalvideosfortoddlers #babies #videosforbabies #toddlervideos #dolls #doll ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website www.songsforlittles.com ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/ #SongsForLittles</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="73822" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="35007640"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:uLsC9aK32QA</id>
<yt:videoId>uLsC9aK32QA</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>Animal Sounds for Toddlers and Babies - Talking Time on the Farm Video - Speech, Songs, Signs Song</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=uLsC9aK32QA"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2020-10-30T13:00:11+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-09T00:08:06+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>Animal Sounds for Toddlers and Babies - Talking Time on the Farm Video - Speech, Songs, Signs Song</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/uLsC9aK32QA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/uLsC9aK32QA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>This video is animal sounds for toddlers and babies. Join us on the farm in this “Talking Time” video that encourages speech with songs and play. We have an animal sounds song for each animal. This video uses techniques recommended by speech therapists to encourage children to use their voices, mimic sounds, animal noises and learn to talk while having fun! It also uses simple songs with gestures, which help children learn to imitate and encourage language and learning. If you think your child may have a speech delay, definitely talk with your pediatrician. You may qualify for free speech therapy through your state's early intervention program. You can also get evaluated by a speech therapist. You deserve help and are not alone! Rachel has a masters in music education and teaches preschool music. She is not a speech therapist but she has worked with speech therapists on techniques and ideas. If you are in New York City and are seeking a speech therapist, check out www.chatterboxnyc.com The brilliant speech therapists at Chatter Box are highly recommended and helped with our “Speech Techniques for Toddlers” video. We also include many songs in our videos because simple songs are shown to help with the development of language and gestures! Gestures and imitation are building blocks of language. We also include some sign language. Baby sign language can help with the development of language and will not impede the development of language at all! This video may also be helpful to children with apraxia, autism, down syndrome and other developmental delays and special needs. We hope the speech activities, exercises, and training are helpful! On our channel, we have many more speech practice videos (see our speech playlist) and we also have free preschool class videos (see our preschool class playlist) and full music classes! We have videos for babies, videos for toddlers and videos for kids. Our videos for toddlers are in English. In our videos we work on speech and language, milestones, gestures, pretend play, social emotional learning, dramatic play, art, music, math, science, circle time, finger plays, sensory play and many more activities! We’d love for you to become part of our Songs for Littles family! #animalsounds #animalsoundsfortoddlers #farmanimalsounds #animalsoundsforbabies #speechdelay #speechfortoddlers #speechdevelopment #firstwords #farmanimals #babysignlanguage #animalsoundssong Rachel teaches preschool music to young kids, toddlers, and babies and has a master's in music education from NYU. She has also been a toddler teacher and has a sweet 2-year-old boy who inspired her online baby music classes and learning videos! ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website www.songsforlittles.com ♥︎ Sign-up for our newsletter https://www.songsforlittles.com/mailinglist ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="18497" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="13417591"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
<entry>
<id>yt:video:-1DYsiKC7b4</id>
<yt:videoId>-1DYsiKC7b4</yt:videoId>
<yt:channelId>UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</yt:channelId>
<title>First Sentences for Toddlers | Learn to Talk | Toddler Speech Delay | Speech Practice Video English</title>
<link rel="alternate" href="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/watch?v=-1DYsiKC7b4"/>
<author>
<name>Ms Rachel - Toddler Learning Videos</name>
<uri>vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/channel/UCG2CL6EUjG8TVT1Tpl9nJdg</uri>
</author>
<published>2021-07-28T17:24:32+00:00</published>
<updated>2023-06-23T15:35:40+00:00</updated>
<media:group>
<media:title>First Sentences for Toddlers | Learn to Talk | Toddler Speech Delay | Speech Practice Video English</media:title>
<media:content url="vnd.youtube.kids://https://www.youtubekids.com/v/-1DYsiKC7b4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
<media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/-1DYsiKC7b4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
<media:description>This educational video teaches the most common and useful first sentences and phrases for toddlers! Have your child learn to talk with a real teacher, Ms Rachel! When Ms Rachel was teaching her little boy first sentences, she couldn’t find a video that showed sentences she wanted him to learn, such as “Up, mama! and “I want juice, please!” She ended up making him his own personal video of first sentences that worked wonderfully for him! Now she’s made this video for you and your child to practice first sentences! This video may be helpful for children with a speech delays, but if your child has a speech delay, take these steps to ensure that they get the help they need to thrive! 1. Talk to your pediatrician about your concerns 2. Call your state’s early intervention program and request an evaluation (your child may qualify for free speech therapy and other therapies if needed) 3. You could also seek out a private speech therapist for an evaluation and speech therapy if needed! Tip: A great first sentence to practice is “I want milk” (or something your child really likes! For example TV, iPad, juice, toy) Here’s how you can help your child, gently prompting their signs hand over hand and having them say the word (if they can speak single words)  1. You can help them point to themselves for “I” as you or they say "I" 2. Help them do the sign for “want” as you or they say “want” 3. Help them do the sign for “milk” as you or they say “milk”  Then give them the milk right away and say, “Great job asking for milk!” For children who have special needs, it may also may be helpful to show a visual for each word such as a PECS system. "Georgie" puppet Copyright 2016 - David Fino  The Brooklyn Puppet Conspiracy. Used with Permission. Ms Rachel has a masters degree in music education from NYU. She studies early childhood education and leadership through courses and trainings at Harvard and Bank Street College. She has also been a toddler teacher at a school for children with special needs including autism, apraxia, speech delays, developmental delays, down syndrome and cerebral palsy. She has worked in homes to support families with children with special needs. She believes all children are gifted, precious and are our teachers as well!  We have many toddler learning videos, baby learning videos, preschool learning videos, speech practice videos and early intervention skills practice videos. We have videos with speech cues and close ups of the mouth that may be helpful for children with childhood apraxia of speech or a motor speech delay. They may also be helpful for kids with ASD (autism spectrum disorder) We hope you’ll come to our homepage and check out more videos to help your little one learn and thrive! If you have a baby, 1 year old, 2 year old, 3 year old, 4 year old or 5 year old, you can find a video to suit your needs on our YouTube page. We put your baby first and not entertainment value. We are very seriously about making high quality, educational interactive videos backed by research. On our team we have a speech therapist, occupational therapist, reading specialist, early chilhood curriculum expert and a child and family therapist. No matter what you are looking for, we have the best educational video for your toddler. #firstsentences #firstphrases #firstsentencesfortoddlers #speechdelay #videosfortoddlers #toddlerlearningvideo #learntotalk #English #speech #toddlershows #toddlerlearning #songsforlittles ♥︎ Subscribe to support our YouTube channel https://bit.ly/2YldegF ♥︎ Visit our website www.songsforlittles.com ♥︎ Like us on Facebook https://www.facebook.com/songsforlittles ♥︎ Follow us on Instagram https://www.instagram.com/songsforlittles/</media:description>
<media:community>
<media:starRating count="98470" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
<media:statistics views="60557775"/>
</media:community>
</media:group>
</entry>
</feed>
